<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Neil's Blog</title>
    <link href="/yaozhifeng.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="/yaozhifeng.net/" />
    <updated>2012-08-08T18:18:25+08:00</updated>
    <id>/yaozhifeng.net/</id>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing articles as writing code]]></title>
        <author><name>Neil</name><uri>http://yaozhifeng.net</uri></author>
        <link href="yaozhifeng.net/2012/writing-articles-as-writing-code.html"/>
        <published>2012-08-08T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2012-08-08T18:18:25+08:00</updated>
        <id>yaozhifeng.net/2012/writing-articles-as-writing-code.html</id>
        <category scheme="/yaozhifeng.net/tag/life/" term="life" label="life" />
        <category scheme="/yaozhifeng.net/tag/blog/" term="blog" label="blog" />
        <category scheme="/yaozhifeng.net/tag/vim/" term="vim" label="vim" />
        <content type="html" xml:base="yaozhifeng.net" xml:lang="en">
            <![CDATA[ <p>I have been quite active in writing blogs a few years ago, when the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Live_Spaces">Microsoft Live Space</a> service had not been stopped. It was fun to record a little bit of life on the internet and being &ldquo;social&rdquo;, which means getting feedback from friends who has been connected through MSN Messenger. Until September 2010, Microsoft annouced that it would discontinue Live Spaces. It was a good service.</p>
<p>Then I migrate to wordpress. First at wordpress.com and then hosted at dreamhost.com. But actually, I stopped writing since then. </p>
<p>This week, I found this: <a href="http://lab.lepture.com/liquidluck/">Felix Felicis</a>, a static blog generator. It is so different with wordpress kind of thing in that there&#39;s no database at all. It is just so simple and elegant and interesting, that I decide to try it and start bloging.</p>
<p>With <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Live_Spaces">Felix Felicis</a>, writing blog is no longer like logging in to a web system and fighting with the so called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYG">WISIWIG</a> editor. Instead, now you create your article with a text editor as simple and powerful as <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>, then build it, and deploy to any web server. This is definately not for everyone, this is for prgrammers. And I am a programmer. And now we have <a href="http://git-scm.com/">Git</a>, with which we keep our articles in version control, just as how we control our source code. And we can host our source code (aka, blog articles) on <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>, as every programmers do.</p>
<p>I am thinking the way we blog using fancy database driven system might just simply wrong. As a programmer, now I write my articles with a source code editor, I compile it into HTML, then I publish it. Meanwhile, I source control them with Git. That&#39;s fun!</p>
<p><img src="/media/writing_with_vim.png" alt="Writing with Vim" title="Writing with Vim"/> </p>
]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>